<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on wrhansen.dev</title><link>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on wrhansen.dev</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:08:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Github Actions to Automate My Second Brain</title><link>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/2023/automating-my-second-brain/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 20:15:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/2023/automating-my-second-brain/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="building-a-second-brain-with-notion">Building a Second Brain with Notion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For the past year I have been building my second brain&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> in Notion. I use
Notion daily to store web clippings, research and meeting notes for work, the
books I read, book highlights&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and notes, and even the upcoming movies and
TV shows that I want to watch. The Notion database provides a great user experience
for capturing, filtering and sorting lists of data like that.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>TIL: AWS Elastic Beanstalk</title><link>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/2022/aws-journey-elasticbeanstalk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 20:15:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/2022/aws-journey-elasticbeanstalk/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My immediate family (8 of us total) has a private chat group using the &lt;em>GroupMe&lt;/em> app &lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>
that we have been using for a couple of years now. When we first started using &lt;em>GroupMe&lt;/em>
for our chat, I was happy because it offered an &lt;a href="https://dev.groupme.com/" target="_blank">API&lt;/a>
that you use to enhance the group chat. So I played around with it one weekend
and the &lt;a href="https://github.com/wrhansen/hansenbot" target="_blank">hansenbot&lt;/a> was created.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;code>hansenbot&lt;/code> is a pretty simple django app that exposes a hook URL that you
can setup that &lt;em>GroupMe&lt;/em> will forward all messages in your group to. I created the
&lt;code>hansenbot&lt;/code> to respond to certain commands that are typed in the group chat that
have the following form: &lt;code>!hb &amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code> where &lt;code>!hb&lt;/code> tells the bot that the given
message is a command that it needs to respond to and &lt;code>&amp;lt;command&amp;gt;&lt;/code> is one of the
preconfigured commands that I created that report information back to the
&lt;em>GroupMe&lt;/em> group. These commands I created range from telling &amp;ldquo;dad jokes&amp;rdquo;, giving
current weather information for all the locations where my family lives and
information about the next upcoming birthday.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Email for Professionals</title><link>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/2022/email-for-professionals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 23:24:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/2022/email-for-professionals/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="problem">Problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my professional career, from time to time, I get forwarded an email, out of
the blue from a colleague, and this email has a message that reads &amp;ldquo;Hey Wes, can
you do this for me?&amp;rdquo;. Following this seemingly simple message is a week-long
thread of thirty emails between several people and I am the lucky individual who
gets added to the chain in hopes that I can resolve the issue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Docs for Developers</title><link>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/2022/docs-for-developers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 20:28:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/2022/docs-for-developers/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="book-review">Book Review&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is my review (and notes) of the book &lt;a href="https://docsfordevelopers.com/" title="Official Book Site" target="_blank">Docs for Developers: An Engineer&amp;rsquo;s
Field Guide to Technical Writing&lt;/a> by Jared Bhatti, Zachary Sarah Corleissen,
Jen Lambourne, David Nunez, and Heidi Waterhouse. I purchased this book because
I am passionate about good developer docs. I can easily spot good developer docs
while working on a project but find it hard to write them myself in a way that
is useful to myself and others. This is a skill that I want to get better at so
I thought that this book would help.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How is This Blog Made?</title><link>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/2022/how-is-this-blog-made/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 11:57:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/2022/how-is-this-blog-made/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="technology">Technology&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This blog is written in markdown and uses the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/" target="_blank">Hugo&lt;/a> static
site generator. I found a nice minimalist theme called &lt;a href="">terminal&lt;/a> that styles
the site the way you see here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deployment">Deployment&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For simplicity and ease-of-use, I decided to host this blog on github pages and
take advantage of free static site hosting. You can find the contents of this
blog in the following repo: &lt;a href="https://github.com/wrhansen/wrhansen.github.io" target="_blank">link&lt;/a>.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to use because github automatically builds and deploys anytime you
merge a new commit to the &lt;code>main&lt;/code> branch.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>