<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on wesrhansen.dev blog</title><link>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on wesrhansen.dev blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 23:24:16 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Email for Professionals</title><link>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/email-for-professionals/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Apr 2022 23:24:16 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/email-for-professionals/</guid><description>Problem In my professional career, from time to time, I get forwarded an email, out of the blue from a colleague, and this email has a message that reads &amp;ldquo;Hey Wes, can you do this for me?&amp;rdquo;. Following this seemingly simple message is a week-long thread of thirty emails between several people and I am the lucky individual who gets added to the chain in hopes that I can resolve the issue.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="problem">Problem&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>In my professional career, from time to time, I get forwarded an email, out of
the blue from a colleague, and this email has a message that reads &amp;ldquo;Hey Wes, can
you do this for me?&amp;rdquo;. Following this seemingly simple message is a week-long
thread of thirty emails between several people and I am the lucky individual who
gets added to the chain in hopes that I can resolve the issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is one of those office etiquette pet peeves of mine that I find frustrating
at times. It is frustrating because the expectation is that I am supposed to
follow the clues in a long chain to even figure out what my colleague is asking
of me. This is an indication to me that my time is not respected, and actually
makes me less willing to help out my fellow colleagues.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="etiquette-be-precise">Etiquette: Be Precise&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>What is the proper etiquette here? How are you as a professional supposed to
communicate to your colleague the important information that is stretched across
a quagmire of hastily constructed emails? It&amp;rsquo;s easy, and it starts with
respecting your colleague&amp;rsquo;s time. Just like yourself, your colleague has an
endless list of things to do so you should respect that time. If you expect them
to give you a timely response and help out with the email you just forwarded,
make sure to be very precise with your message that you write to them. Don&amp;rsquo;t
make them go through all the past emails to try to figure out the context of
what you&amp;rsquo;re asking. Instead, summarize precisely the key points in the chain
and explicitly ask what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for your colleague to do for you. Their
time is as valuable as their&amp;rsquo;s so don&amp;rsquo;t waste it!&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Docs for Developers</title><link>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/docs-for-developers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 20:28:50 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/docs-for-developers/</guid><description>Book Review This is my review (and notes) of the book Docs for Developers: An Engineer&amp;rsquo;s Field Guide to Technical Writing by Jared Bhatti, Zachary Sarah Corleissen, Jen Lambourne, David Nunez, and Heidi Waterhouse. I purchased this book because I am passionate about good developer docs. I can easily spot good developer docs while working on a project but find it hard to write them myself in a way that is useful to myself and others.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="book-review">Book Review&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This is my review (and notes) of the book &lt;a href="https://docsfordevelopers.com/" title="Official Book Site">Docs for Developers: An Engineer&amp;rsquo;s
Field Guide to Technical Writing&lt;/a> by Jared Bhatti, Zachary Sarah Corleissen,
Jen Lambourne, David Nunez, and Heidi Waterhouse. I purchased this book because
I am passionate about good developer docs. I can easily spot good developer docs
while working on a project but find it hard to write them myself in a way that
is useful to myself and others. This is a skill that I want to get better at so
I thought that this book would help.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="chapter-1-notes">Chapter 1 Notes&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This chapter is all about understanding your audience. This chapter seems geared
more towards client-focused documentation, where you have a product (like an API)
that you want clients to read. While this information is useful, and complete,
it seems to be outside the scope of what docs I typically write, which is
supplemental developer docs for internal teams to use to understand some service
that my team maintains. I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely keep the points raised in this chapter
in mind for when I have a need for more client-focused documentation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I like the idea of a friction log. The authors define it as:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A &lt;em>friction log&lt;/em> is a journal in which you try your software as a user would
and record your experiences. To record your experience, log each step
sequentially, noting the behavior you expect and the actual behavior of your
software.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve never done anything explicity like this, however I can relate to the
process. To put it into my own experiences, my team typically writes docs for
the rest of the team to consume, as I mentioned before. We have an agreement on
the team, that if any dev reads docs and they don&amp;rsquo;t quite make sense to the dev
reading them it is their responsibility to update the docs to make more sense.
This to me has some relevance to a &lt;em>friction log&lt;/em> because you have a real-world
scenario where your intended audience is reading/working through your
documentation and they just happen to also have the ability to improve it
directly.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overall-review">Overall Review&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>After chapter 1 I found 90% of the book pretty standard information and got
nothing out of the information that I really thought was worthwhile. For this
reason I stopped taking individual chapter notes. There was one section in
one of the final chapters that explained some of the most common ways to
organize your docs site. It gave me some ideas of how to organize the docs that
I write for work in a way that makes the information grouped in a way that&amp;rsquo;s easy
to find stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I give this book 2 stars.&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>How is This Blog Made?</title><link>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/how-is-this-blog-made/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 11:57:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://blog.wrhansen.dev/posts/how-is-this-blog-made/</guid><description>Technology This blog is written in markdown and uses the Hugo static site generator. I found a nice minimalist theme called terminal that styles the site the way you see here.
Deployment For simplicity and ease-of-use, I decided to host this blog on github pages and take advantage of free static site hosting. You can find the contents of this blog in the following repo: link. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to use because github automatically builds and deploys anytime you merge a new commit to the main branch.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="technology">Technology&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>This blog is written in markdown and uses the &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a> static
site generator. I found a nice minimalist theme called &lt;a href="">terminal&lt;/a> that styles
the site the way you see here.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="deployment">Deployment&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For simplicity and ease-of-use, I decided to host this blog on github pages and
take advantage of free static site hosting. You can find the contents of this
blog in the following repo: &lt;a href="https://github.com/wrhansen/wrhansen.github.io">link&lt;/a>.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to use because github automatically builds and deploys anytime you
merge a new commit to the &lt;code>main&lt;/code> branch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, they allow the option to use your own custom domain for the URL
so I opted with my own domain: &lt;a href="https://blog.wrhansen.dev/">https://blog.wrhansen.dev/&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="references">References&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Host Hugo on Github: &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/hosting-and-deployment/hosting-on-github/">link&lt;/a>.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hugo terminal theme: &lt;a href="https://github.com/panr/hugo-theme-terminal">link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Github Pages: &lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/">link&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item></channel></rss>